JOHN JANG

Product Designer

+1 647 553 3499

iscolbe9675@gmail.com

My portfolio

SUMMARY

A Product Designer, graduated from York University in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, with over a year of professional experience in crafting user experience that suits the branding and another year of experience in web development. I am proficient in designing products from scratch till the launch, while considering the development perspective such as the User Interface development, CI/CD pipeline, deployment, etc. My strengths include strategic designing, initiating projects, and leading communications with internal and external teams. By nature, I am analytical, perceptive, and enjoy problem-solving. Outside of work, I am a runner, dancer, and a potential traveler.

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer

OperateEase

08 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Developed a comprehensive design system to standardize UI components and hosted UX Design workshops to align with stakeholders and gather insights from users
- Led the design of an inventory management system, optimizing room occupancy and supply management, increasing efficiency by 60%
- Collaborated closely with engineering teams to ensure design feasibility and maintain a high standard of quality across all features

Product Designer Intern

The Sakhi

06 / 2024 ~ 10 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

- Designed culturally specific shopping experiences, achieving a 3.5% CTR in the pilot phase
- Conducted regular design critique sessions with Shopify developers to refine features and functionality based on feedback
- Identified 8+ user flow pain points and improved the shopping experience through data-driven adjustments aligned with business goals

UX Designer TuGo Travel

03 / 2024 ~ 05 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

- Enhanced the user engagement in the exploration and payment process, boosting average engagement time to 10 minutes
- Prioritized and aligned design initiatives with product objectives, focusing on ROI and user satisfaction

UX/UI Design Apprentice

06 / 2022 ~ 08 / 2022 | Remote, Toronto

- Conducted user research with **30 participants** gathering insights that informed feature prioritization and usability
- Revamped video call service design, driving an 80% increase in usage and a 60% rise in call duration

VOLUNTEER

Web Development Apprentice Tech Fleet Professional Association

08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

 Collaborated with UX designers to develop user-friendly applications, ensuring design integrity alongside development teams

UX/UI Design Apprentice

Tech Fleet Professional Association

04 / 2023 ~ 07 / 2023 | Remote, Toronto

 Designed and implemented a location-based, user-friendly search functionality serving over 5,000 users monthly

EDUCATION

UX Design

York University

North York, Ontario

Web Development Bootcamp

Dream Coding Academy September 2022 ~ July 2023

Remote, Toronto

Psychology & Neuroscience

University of New Brunswick September 2013 ~ June 2017 Fredericton, NB

TOOLS & SKILLS

Figma, Figjam, Miro, Wireframing, Sketching, Typography, Prototyping, Mock-ups, A/B Testing, Usability Testing Waterfall, User-Interface Design, User Research HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vite, MongoDB, Express.js, Axios

OTHER LINKS

<u>LinkedIn - John Jang</u>

<u>My Web Development Portfolio</u>

<u>My Github Profile</u>

OTHER INFO

Portfolio password: portfolio